validclick.net 2008-02-07

# ValidClick.com Validate your Traffic

Please read this policy to understand what information ValidClick collects, how we use it, and what choices you have regarding the use and sharing of your information when using the ValidClick Advertising Solutions (VS) sites as a visitor. The VS sites include sites that are branded " ValidClick Advertising Solutions" and " ValidClick Search Marketing" as well as sites on the following domains: www.searchvortal.com, advertising.ValidClick.com, solutions.ValidClick.com, and summitseries.ValidClick.com. For more information on ValidClick's other privacy policies that apply to subscribers and users of other ValidClick products and services, including the ValidClick Shopping, Travel and Directory Submit programs, please read the ValidClick Terms and Conditions. 

**What this policy covers**   
This policy covers business contact information, such as name, email address, telephone number and address and other work-related information, that visitors provide to VS online on publicly available VS sites (where advertiser login is not required). If you are a business enrolled in advertiser programs that are subject to the Advertiser Master Services Terms and Conditions, Insertion Order(s) or other advertising or marketing agreements (collectively, "Advertising Agreement"), please refer to your Advertising Agreement to learn more about how ValidClick may use information about your business. The terms of such business agreements supersede the provisions of this Privacy Policy. 

**Types of information we collect and how we use it**   
The following describes what information ValidClick Advertising Solutions collects from visitors to the VS sites as well as outside the ValidClick network of web sites, and how we may use it: 

  1. **Email addresses and related information**   
There may be opportunities for visitors to the site to sign-up to receive email communications. Visitors may subscribe by providing an email address and other requested information. Recipients of email marketing messages will have the opportunity to unsubscribe from future messages via the link(s) provided within the message.
  2. **Search**   
The Bid4keywords.com site offers web search functionality to visitors. Anonymous cookies are used on the site in connection with the search functionality.
  3. **Cookies and web beacons on VS web sites**  
ValidClick accesses [ValidClick domain cookies](http://www.myspacevortal.com/privacy.html) and may use [ValidClick web beacons](http://www.myspacevortal.com/privacy.html) when you visit the VS sites or other sites on the ValidClick domain. ValidClick and certain partners working on behalf of ValidClick, also use web beacons on the VS sites. ValidClick may share site usage information about visitors to the VS sites with third-party advertising companies for the purpose of targeting and measuring the effectiveness of our Internet advertisements on this site and other sites. For this purpose, ValidClick and these third-party advertising companies note some of the pages you visit on our sites through the use of web beacons. 

The information collected by these third-party advertising companies through the use of these web beacons is not personally identifiable. For more information about our third-party advertisers, including how to opt out of their targeting programs, please visit their sites: [Omniture (207.net)](http://www.omniture.com/), [Doubleclick](http://www.doubleclick.com/), [Commission Junction](http://www.cj.com/) and [Performics](http://www.performics.com/). 

In addition to the above, ValidClick's email delivery vendor may employ web beacons and cookies within HTML email messages sent on our behalf and on the VS sites. The use of cookies and web beacons described above help ValidClick to measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use the VS sites. 

  1. **VS cookies and web beacons outside the ValidClick network of web sites**  
ValidClick Search Marketing offers advertisers tools that allow them to better understand the performance of their online marketing campaigns. For more information about these tools and the web beacons and cookies used, please read the [ValidClick Search Marketing Tools Privacy Statement](http://www.myspacevortal.com/privacy.html). 
  2. **Promotions and sweepstakes**   
From time to time, ValidClick may sponsor or host promotions and sweepstakes where we collect information. Use and sharing of this information will be disclosed in promotion and sweepstakes rules or on the page where you sign-up.
  3. **IP addresses and information specific to your computer**  
SearchVortal logs IP information when you visit our sites, including the VS sites. In addition to this information, ValidClick collects information that your computer's browser automatically reports to us such as information about your operating system and browser version. 

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**  
ValidClick does not rent, sell or share personally identifiable information about visitors to the VS sites. However, ValidClick may share this information with selected partners, vendors, agents or others who work on our behalf, in order to provide products or services you've requested, or when we have your permission. In addition, ValidClick may share information about you if ValidClick is acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, ValidClick will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

Please note that we may also share information in the event that we are asked to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, or as otherwise permitted by law. 

**Other**   
ValidClick may update this policy. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by placing a prominent notice on this site. 

The VS sites are not targeted at children and are not intended for use by children under the age of 13. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at the following: 

ValidClick Inc.      
SearchVortal Advertising Solutions - Privacy Policy Issues      
6320 Canoga Ave. Suite 250      
Woodland Hills, CA 91367   

Effective Date: MAY 1, 2006
